<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<task id="usermanagement-EditMultipleUsers">
    <title>Edit Multiple Users</title>
    <taskbody>
        <prereq>
           <ul>
            <li>An user with SECURITY_ADMIN role is available in ENM system and at least two users with assigned administrator role are configured in the system with default target group ALL.</li>
            <li>To check currently assigned role(s), select the User ID on the top right hand corner,
           and click <b>View User Profile</b> from the drop-down list. Assigned roles are displayed.
           </li>
           <li>The TG1 target group is available in ENM system.
           </li>
           </ul>
        </prereq>
        <context>
            <p>
                <b>Objective</b>
            </p>
            <p>This tutorial explains how to assign to more users the Amos_administrator system role with TG1 target group.</p>
            <p>
                <b>Outline</b>
            </p>
            <ol>
                <li>
                    <xref href="#1">Click Edit Profile</xref>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <xref href="#2">Update Users Details</xref>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <xref href="#3">Edit Roles and Target Groups</xref>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <xref href="#4">Edit Authentication</xref>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <xref href="#5">Go to Summary tab</xref>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <xref href="#6">Save the Users</xref>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <xref href="#7">Click Finish</xref>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <xref href="#8">Repeat Steps from Step 1 to Step 9 to Assign TG1 Target Group</xref>
                </li>

            </ol>
        </context>

        <steps>
            <step id="1">
                <cmd>Click Edit Profile</cmd>
                <info>
                   <ol>
                     <li>Launch <xref scope="external" href="/#usermanagement">
                            User Management.</xref></li>
                     <li>Select two or more users from the users list and click <b>Edit Profile</b>.
                         The <b>Edit User Profiles</b> page is displayed.
                     </li>
                   </ol>
                </info>
            </step>

            <step id="2">
               <cmd>Update Users Details</cmd>
               <info>
                  <ol>
                    <li>Select the checkbox <b>Modify Status</b> (optional).
                    </li>
                    <li>Select the <b>Status</b>.
                    </li>
                    <li>Select the checkbox <b>Modify Description</b> (optional).
                    </li>
                    <li>Enter the <b>Description</b>.
                    </li>
                  </ol>
               </info>
            </step>

            <step id="3">
                <cmd>Edit Roles and Target Groups</cmd>
                <info>
                  <ol>
                    <li>
                        Click <b>Roles and Target Groups</b> section or click <b>Next -></b>.
                    </li>
                    <li>Select the checkbox <b>Modify Roles and Target Groups</b> (optional).
                    </li>
                    <li>Select the role(s) from the list to assign to the users.
                    </li>
                    <li>Click <b>Service Target Group to Assign</b> and select NONE as target group to assign and click on <b>Apply</b> from the <b>Assign Service Target Groups</b> panel.
                    </li>
                    </ol>
                </info>
            </step>

            <step id="4">
               <cmd>Edit Authentication</cmd>
               <info>
                 <ol>
                   <li>
                     Click <b>Authentication</b> section or click <b>Next -></b>.
                   </li>
                   <li>Select the checkbox <b>Modify Authentication Mode</b> (optional) to update the authentication mode for the users.
                   </li>
                   <li>Select the checkbox <b>Modify Password Ageing</b> (optional) to update the password aging setting for the users.
                   </li>
                   <li>Enter details for the password aging:
                      <ul>
                        <li>Select <b>Use System Settings</b></li>
                      </ul>
                       or
                       <ul>
                        <li>select <b>Customize Password Ageing</b> and enter the related details.
                        </li>
                      </ul>
                    </li>
                 </ol>
               </info>
            </step>

            <step id="5">
                <cmd>Go to Summary</cmd>
            <info>
                <p>
                     Click <b>Summary</b> section or click <b>Next -></b>. The summary of the entered changes is displayed.
                </p>
            </info>
            </step>

            <step id="6">
                <cmd>Save the Users</cmd>
                <info>
                <p>
                    Click <b>Apply</b> to apply the changes.
                </p>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step id="7">
                <cmd>Click Finish</cmd>
                <info>
                <p>
                    Click <b>Finish</b> to be redirected to users list.
                </p>
            </info>
            </step>
            <step id="8">
                <cmd>Repeat Steps from Step 1 to Step 8 to Assign TG1 Target Group</cmd>
                <info>
                <p>
                    Repeat all steps from 1 to 9 to assign TG1 target group to system roles for the selected users. The only difference is that from the <b>Assign Service Target Groups</b> panel the TG1 target group has to be selected instead of NONE for step 6.
                </p>
                <p>For more information on editing more user profiles, see the <i>
                            <xref href="../ui.xml#editmultipleusers">Edit Multiple Users</xref></i>.
                </p>
                </info>
            </step>

        </steps>
        <result>
            <p>Users are updated.</p>
        </result>

    </taskbody>
</task>



